# DAVID ALISTAIR MEADE JR.

+44 7507 743429 | davidmeadejnr@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Website | GitHub

Software Engineer | London

#### PROFILE

Graduated from a renowned software engineering degree program funded by Santander. Winner of the Google 2022 Project Data Hack and has worked with two web3 startups backed by VCs. With experience in platform engineering within a technology consultancy firm for public and private sector clients. Interested in leveraging code and refining ML models for customer-centric products.

#### TECH STACK

- Automation & DevOps Tools: Azure, AWS, CI/CD, Terraform, Scripting, Kubernetes, Docker, Grafana, Prometheus, Test-Driven Development, Git,
- Frontend: TypeScript, JavaScript, React, Next.JS, React Native, Angular, HTML/CSS, TailwindCSS, Chakra UI
- Backend: Python, FastAPI, SQL, PostgreSQL, NodeJS, Java, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB

#### EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (DEVOPS) 2023 - Present

Hybrid Capgemini

- Provided Azure and AWS expertise to the UK Government (DEFRA), public & private sector clients.
- Facilitated discussions and promoted agile practices, supporting deployments and maintaining CI/CD pipelines, expediting code delivery efficiently.
- Implemented Docker containerization and Kubernetes orchestration to streamline deployment and reduce environment inconsistencies.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND) 2022 - 2022

Flooz

Remote

- · Improved navigation UI, increasing traffic and trading volume, resulting in more user engagement and platform revenue.
- Enhanced "swap token" UX with TypeScript, boosting trading volume on partner platforms, leading to increased transaction volume and revenue.
- · Implemented regression tests, optimising platform stability, resulting in a smoother user experience and fewer bugs.

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND)

2021 - 2022

Astraverse

Remote

- Used React and TypeScript to build the v1 website, creating a centralised hub of company information, benefiting VCs and consumers.
- Developed 2440 Solana-based NFTs, supporting the founder's NFT pitch to Dennis Rodman's team, leading to progressive negotiations.

### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING DEGREE APPRENTICE (FULL-STACK)

2017 - 2022

- On-site
- Applied Agile and Angular for scalability with TypeScript, accelerating the delivery of front-end tickets, enabling the innovation team to achieve targets.
- Built an in-house learning platform using Angular and TypeScript, improving engineer collaboration, increasing cross-team collaboration.
- By using Angular and TypeScript, enhanced the team board UX/UI, improving product team workflows.

#### PROJECTS

#### GOOGLE PROJECT DATA HACKATHON (Joint 1st)

• Built and pitched a startup proof-of-concept with 3 others to Google senior management, winning the Google 2022 project data hackathon.

# QUALIFICATIONS

# DISTRIBUTED SYSTEMS (CHAINLINK CERTIFIED BLOCKCHAIN DEVELOPER)

2022 - 2022

#### Imperial College London

- Developed expertise in distributed systems concepts and their real-world applications.
- Created smart contracts leveraging Chainlink oracle technology.
- Implemented secure off-chain data access patterns for blockchain applications.
- Generated verifiable random numbers through Chainlink's infrastructure.
- Developed professional-grade smart contract development techniques.

# BSC, DIGITAL & TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS, COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

2017 - 2022

#### **BPP University**

- 1 of 14 selected for the degree apprenticeship program out of over 900 applicants.
- Software Engineer specialism.
- Top percentile achiever in final year software engineering modules.